<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nirantk.com/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Retrieval Augmented Generation Best Practices</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/rag-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/rag-best-practices/</guid><description>Retrieval and Ranking Matter! #
Chunking #
Including section title in your chunks improves that, so does keywords from the documents Different token-efficient separators in your chunks e.g. ### is a single token in GPT Examples #
Few examples are better than no examples Examples at the start and end have the highest weight, the middle ones are kinda forgotten by the LLM Re Rankers #
Latency permitting — use a ReRanker — Cohere, Sentence Transformers and BGE have decent ones out of the box</description></item><item><title>Tax Tips for Consultants with Foreign Income</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/foreign-income/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/foreign-income/</guid><description>Managing taxation and financial compliance as a consultant in India involves several considerations: GST to the benefits of Section 44ADA and the complexities of foreign entity considerations, consultants must juggle multiple aspects to ensure compliance and tax optimization. I&amp;rsquo;m sharing what I know in the hopes it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to others.
1. Compliance: GST, LUT and FIRC #
Threshold: Acquiring a GST number becomes almost mandatory once your income surpasses some X=20 lakhs INR in a given financial year.</description></item><item><title>Meetup Parameters</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/meetup-params/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/meetup-params/</guid><description>This is based on organising GenerativeAI Meetups in Bengaluru, India. This is a living document and will be updated as we learn more.
Venue #
Date &amp;amp; Time &amp;amp; Duration: Choose suitable timing and duration. Pick something that works for your community. Consider weekday and weekend meetups both. Example: 4:00-5.00pm start on a Saturday works great in BLR! Chennai did a GenAI meetup on Saturday morning &amp;ndash; since that city wakes up early, it worked well for them.</description></item><item><title>Qdrant vs pgvector - Results from the 1M OpenAI Benchmark</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/pgvector-vs-qdrant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/pgvector-vs-qdrant/</guid><description>You may have considered using PostgreSQL&amp;rsquo;s pgvector extension for vector similarity search. There are good reasons why this option is strictly inferior to dedicated vector search engines, such as Qdrant.
We ran both benchmarks using the ann-benchmarks solely dedicated to processing vector data. The difference in performance is quite staggering.
Query Speed #
Final results show that pgvector lags behind Qdrant by a factor of 15 when it comes to throughput.</description></item><item><title>Airbnb's Metric Store: Minerva</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/minerva/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/minerva/</guid><description>Data lineage is a problem because most companies have several tables and queries before humans consume it!
This has well known challenges: changes do not propagate downstream from the source, and reliable (fresh, updated or complete) data is not always available.
What does Minerva do? #
I was expecting Minerva to a database (collection of tables), but it turns out that Minerva is what I&amp;rsquo;ll call: Data Transformation Manager.
It overlaps quite a bit with dbt but it&amp;rsquo;s not a pure execution layer.</description></item><item><title>Beyond First 90 Days</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/beyond-first-90-days/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/beyond-first-90-days/</guid><description>This one&amp;rsquo;s gonna be brief and echoes 2 Less Obvious Ideas to the younger me.
I am assuming that you already know the hygiene factors: Make few promises. Keep most of them and exceed few of them atleast. Get to like the top 5% in the skill of effort estimation for your own work at the very least. And so on.
Contribute to Developer Ecosystem #
Improving any part of the developer ecosystem is useful and visible at the same time.</description></item><item><title>Dos and Don'ts for ML Hiring</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/ml-hiring/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/ml-hiring/</guid><description>This is primarily for my future self. These are observations based on my own experience of 2 years at Verloop.io and helping a few companies hire for similar roles.
Do #
Seniormost hire first: Start by hiring the senior most person you&amp;rsquo;re going to hire. E.g. start by hiring the ML Lead (assuming you already have a CTO) Have a means to tell that your investment in data science is working out or not Closest to User first: Hire the person who will consume the data to build for the user first Sourcing: Begin sourcing early and over-emphasise two channels: Referrals and Portfolios Typically, in India - expect: ~2 months to close a full time role at early career (0-3 years) and ~3 months to close a mid career (3-7 years) and 6+ months to close a senior hire If a developer has open source code contributions in the last 2-3 years, consider waving off the coding or algorithmic challenge to speed up the interview process Pay above market cash salaries In 12-18 months from now, when your ML Engineer will have internalised all the requirements, company culture and built a bunch of important tooling - she would get an offer which is 2-3x of today.</description></item><item><title>Why I Quit Data Science</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/why-i-quit-data-science/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/why-i-quit-data-science/</guid><description>Question from a friend: I am interested in knowing how did you come to this decision of moving to SWE from DS/MLE. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked a variant of this question quite a few times, I thought it would be good to share my answer.
What kind of research did you do to get to this decision? #
I spoke to a lot of people who were both big companies and startups.</description></item><item><title>Anti Skills</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/antiskill/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/antiskill/</guid><description>You learn a well-paying skill and years later - it comes back to hurt you in unexpected ways. That&amp;rsquo;s an Anti Skill.
Consider this hypothetical: You start your software engineering career and build a reputation as someone who is good at iOS development. Each year, the money you make keeps improving as you keep getting better at it.
The downside? You&amp;rsquo;ll find it hard to get job offers outside of iOS development [1]</description></item><item><title>Breaking into NLP</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/breaking-into-nlp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/breaking-into-nlp/</guid><description>Bulk of this is borrowed from notes made my teammate and friend at Verloop.io&amp;rsquo;s NLP/ML team of our conversations. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the liberty to remove our internal slang and some boring stuff.
I want to build a community around me on NLP. How can I get discovered by others?
Broadly speaking, the aim in forming connections can be split into Long Term and Short term. A short term aim would be where you can receive something immediate out of the connections or a particular connection itself.</description></item></channel></rss>