<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writings on Nirant Kasliwal</title>
    <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writings on Nirant Kasliwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 23:29:18 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nirantk.com/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ML Model Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/modelmonitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/modelmonitoring/</guid>
      <description>ML Model Monitoring Mayank asked on Twitter:
 Some ideas/ papers/ tools on monitoring models in production. A use case would be say a classification task over large inputs and I visualise how are the predicted values or even confidence scores very over time?
 Quick Hacks pandas-profiling If you are logging confidence scores, the quickest hack is to load them into a dataframe and visusalize with pandas-profiling: https://github.com/pandas-profiling/pandas-profiling/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best of Python 3 f-strings</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/pythonfstrings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/pythonfstrings/</guid>
      <description>This piece is primarily meant for those new to Python. These include mathematicians, economists, and so on who want to use Python within a Jupyter environment. Here is a quick guide on how to make Best of Jupyter.
Quick Primer If you are familiar with earlier Python versions, here are my top picks on how to move from .format () to this new one:
_fstring = f&amp;#39;Total: {one + two}&amp;#39; # Go f-string!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Bask in Reflected Glory</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/reflectedglory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/reflectedglory/</guid>
      <description>ये जो लोग-बाग हैं, जंगल की आग हैं Ye jo log baag hain, Jungle ki aag hain The people, are jungle fire क्यूँ आग में जलूँ... Kyun aag mein jalun Why should I burn in the fire? ये नाकाम प्यार में, खुश हैं ये हार में Ye nakaam pyaar mein, Khush hai yeh haar mein Defeated in love, they&#39;re happy in defeat इन जैसा क्यूँ बनूँ... Inn jaisa kyun banun Why should I be like them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Silent Rise of PyTorch Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/silentriseofpytorch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/silentriseofpytorch/</guid>
      <description>The Silent Rise of PyTorch Ecosystem While Tensorflow has made peace with Keras as it’s high level API and mxNet now support Gluon — PyTorch is the bare matrix love.
PyTorch has seen rapid adoption in academia and all the industrial labs that I have spoken to as well. One of the reasons people (specially engineers doing experiments) like PyTorch is the ease of debugging.
What I don’t like about PyTorch is it’s incessant requirement of debugging because of inconsistent dimensions problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Talk Tips</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/techtalktips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/techtalktips/</guid>
      <description>Collection of the Best Advice on Internet that I know about on giving a tech talk. Based on responses from my question on Twitter.
Meghana gave a talk based on these tips at PyData Bengaluru   You: Hey, I know something better!
Me: Please tell me about it! Raise a PR. Or reply to the tweet above!
 The Mindset  Presentations Skills Considered Harmful tl;dr: Do not block the message with your actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to prepare for a Data Science job from college?</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/datasciencejob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/datasciencejob/</guid>
      <description>A Getting Started Guide
Let us get our facts straight, shall we?
I am writing from my non-existent but probably relevant experience. I worked in a Machine Learning role at Samsung Research, Bengaluru. It is only 1 of the 4 research enterprises which hire Machine Learning researchers from Indian colleges — the other being Microsoft, Xerox, and IBM Watson.
I am now in a even more Computer Vision focused role for a small enterprise tech company.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>