<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>verloop on Nirant Kasliwal</title>
    <link>https://nirantk.com/tags/verloop.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in verloop on Nirant Kasliwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:09:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nirantk.com/tags/verloop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Org Designs</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/data-org-design.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/data-org-design.html</guid>
      <description>Data Science Org Design While there is plenty of good advice on making ML work and making a career as a Data Scientist - I think very little discussion happens on the organization design for Data Science itself.
 Organization Design is determined by these 3 broad categories:
  Software Engineer vs Research: To what extent is the Machine Learning team responsible for building or integrating with software? How important are Software Engineering skills on the team?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re all Gamers Now</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/stop-larping.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/stop-larping.html</guid>
      <description>When I show up to Dr. Bob’s office, I don’t expect to deal with Bob; I expect to deal with The Doctor. The doctor is not going to behave as Bob, Alice, or Caroline might act, even if that’s who the doctor is. The doctor is going to behave as The Doctor! This is essentially a human user interface. I’m not Samo. I am The Patient. And Alice is The Doctor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: Building a Data Science Team at a Startup</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/case-study-building-a-data-science-team.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/case-study-building-a-data-science-team.html</guid>
      <description>Hello!
If we are meeting for the first time, a short version of my story so far: After doing research engineering for almost 4 years across startups and a BigCo, I joined as an early machine learning engineer at Verloop.io - a B2B startup that makes customer support automation SaaS. We&amp;rsquo;re directly responsible for most Natural Language Processing needs within the business.
While there is plenty of good advice on making ML work and making a career as a Data Scientist, I wanted to write my experience as a manager/early engineer who built out a ML team at a startup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verloop NLP Interview Prep Guide</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/verloop-ml-prep-guide.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/verloop-ml-prep-guide.html</guid>
      <description>Preparation Guide I&amp;rsquo;ve been an early Machine Learning Engineer at Verloop.io for almost 1.5 years, primarily working on NLP problems and now more in an Engineering Manager-ish role.
This is the guide which I sometimes send to our candidates after they submit the Programming Challenge. If a candidate has relevant open source code sample, specially to other repositories we may choose to waive off the Programming Challenge completely.
I originally wrote this to give a chance to folks coming from non-NLP background to get a sense of the problem space a little better.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
