<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nirant Kasliwal</title>
    <link>https://nirantk.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nirant Kasliwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nirantk.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Best of Python 3 f-strings</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/pythonfstrings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/pythonfstrings/</guid>
      <description>This piece is primarily meant for those new to Python. These include mathematicians, economists, and so on who want to use Python within a Jupyter environment. Here is a quick guide on how to make Best of Jupyter.
Quick Primer If you are familiar with earlier Python versions, here are my top picks on how to move from .format () to this new one:
_fstring = f&amp;#39;Total: {one + two}&amp;#39; # Go f-string!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Silent Rise of PyTorch Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/silentriseofpytorch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/silentriseofpytorch/</guid>
      <description>The Silent Rise of PyTorch Ecosystem While Tensorflow has made peace with Keras as it’s high level API and mxNet now support Gluon — PyTorch is the bare matrix love.
PyTorch has seen rapid adoption in academia and all the industrial labs that I have spoken to as well. One of the reasons people (specially engineers doing experiments) like PyTorch is the ease of debugging.
What I don’t like about PyTorch is it’s incessant requirement of debugging because of inconsistent dimensions problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fail Resume</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/failresume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/failresume/</guid>
      <description>A failure resume is, as its name suggests, a list of rejections and setbacks.
This concept originated in academia, but can be applied to improve one’s career, resilience, and approach to challenges in any walk of life.
I’ve organized my setbacks by year (starting with 2016), and what constitutes a “failure” here is based solely on my own judgement. It’s important to not only list the failures, but also learn from them, so I will add reflections to some of them (in progress).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/now/</guid>
      <description>What I’m doing now Work: I look at Machine Learning and Natural Language stuff for Verloop. We help make customer support more humane.
Career: Rather scattered and still exploratory
Personal - Fitness Goal: Be able to run 10 km and dead lift my body weight on the same day in 2021
Torschlusspaniki About the word Torschlusspaniki
My previous workplaces made a serious dent in the size of my dreams. It is only at welcoming meadow work culture at Verloop - that I&amp;rsquo;ve come to feel like going back on the chase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Talk Tips</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/techtalktips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/techtalktips/</guid>
      <description>Collection of the Best Advice on Internet that I know about on giving a tech talk. Based on responses from my question on Twitter.
  Meghana gave a talk based on these tips at PyData Bengaluru
   You: Hey, I know something better!
Me: Please tell me about it! Raise a PR. Or reply to the tweet above!
 The Mindset  Presentations Skills Considered Harmful tl;dr: Do not block the message with your actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to prepare for a Data Science job from college?</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/datasciencejob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/datasciencejob/</guid>
      <description>A Getting Started Guide
Let us get our facts straight, shall we?
I am writing from my non-existent but probably relevant experience. I worked in a Machine Learning role at Samsung Research, Bengaluru. It is only 1 of the 4 research enterprises which hire Machine Learning researchers from Indian colleges — the other being Microsoft, Xerox, and IBM Watson.
I am now in a even more Computer Vision focused role for a small enterprise tech company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hiya! You found me. I&amp;rsquo;m Nirant.
Linkedin | Github | Twitter
About NLP in Python: Quickstart Guide Wrote a Book for Programmers to Brew NLP Recipes (Jan 2019) 
 Written with code examples and programmer-first mindset. Try it out yourself on Github Includes Text Embedding, Linguistics 101, Ensemble Modeling, Chatbots with small data, ML and Deep learning for text classification using tools like spaCy, PyTorch, &amp;amp; gensim. Published in US, UK and India  Tech Talks  inMobi Tech Talks: A Nightmare on the LM Street; Slides Wingify DevFest: NLP for Indian Languages; Slides, Youtube PyData Bengaluru Inaugral Talk: Quiz Generation with spaCy; Youtube  Community Contributions  Awesome Project Ideas - Curated list of machine learning (mostly deep learning) project ideas with datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>