<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nirant Kasliwal</title>
    <link>https://nirantk.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nirant Kasliwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nirantk.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bezos &amp; Amazon Inc.</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/amazon/</guid>
      <description>Bezos &amp;amp; Amazon Inc. This short page is my personal collection of lessons, ideas, observation, &amp;amp; notes.
I don&amp;rsquo;t expect them to be useful for anyone except me, but hey - if you do, say Hi to me on Twitter
Introductory This is mostly obvious stuff. - Book - The Everything Store - Betting on Things that Never Change by Morgan Housel
Observations These are nebulous ideas or dots. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how they connect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failure Resume</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/failresume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/failresume/</guid>
      <description>Failure Resume :)
A failure resume is, as its name suggests, a list of rejections and setbacks.
This concept originated in academia, but can be applied to improve one’s career, resilience, and approach to challenges in any walk of life.
I’ve organized my setbacks by year (starting with 2016), and what constitutes a “failure” here is based solely on my own judgement. It’s important to not only list the failures, but also learn from them, so I will add reflections to some of them (in progress).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Talk Tips</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/techtalktips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/techtalktips/</guid>
      <description>Collection of the Best Advice on Internet that I know about on giving a tech talk. Based on responses from my question on Twitter.
 You: Hey, I know something better!
Me: Please tell me about it! Raise a PR. Or reply to the tweet above!
 The Mindset  Presentations Skills Considered Harmful tl;dr: Do not block the message with your actions. Put in the work to get the message across.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Nirant Kasliwal Linkedin | Github | Twitter
What&amp;rsquo;s New Inaugural Speaker at PyData Bangalore  Talk: Quiz Generation with spaCy; video  Kaggle Kernel - you can fork and play with this using Kaggle&amp;rsquo;s Compute Notebook with Quiz Generation Examples from Github Repo on NLP in Python Reading on Dependency Parsing: Speech &amp;amp; Language Processing by Daniel Jurafsky, Chp.13   Active Project: Awesome NLP  Primary Maintainer for Awesome-NLP, which is also featured in Github&amp;rsquo;s Official Machine Learning Collection Curated list of Natural Language Processing Resources with 75+ contributors, 8k+ stars, 1k+ forks  First Runner&amp;rsquo;s Up at the Future Group Datathon  Two stage Machine Learning hackathon called Tathastu, working on recommendation systems and item information extraction problems (March 2019) Judged by a jury from Palantir and Future Group Consumer &amp;amp; Data Lab  Tech Talks  inMobi Tech Talks: A Nightmare on the LM Street; Slides Wingify DevFest: NLP for Indian Languages; Slides, Youtube  NLP in Python: Quickstart Guide Authored a Book for Programmers to Brew NLP Recipes (Jan 2019)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/articles/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/essays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/essays/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>