<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nirant Kasliwal</title>
    <link>https://nirantk.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nirant Kasliwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 23:09:05 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nirantk.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 23:09:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/now/</guid>
      <description>What I’m doing now Work: I lead Machine Learning Engineering for Verloop - we help automate conversations between you and a business. Life: Rather scattered and still confused
Torschlusspaniki / Panicking About the word
My previous workplaces made a serious dent in the size of my dreams. It is only at welcoming meadow-like work culture at Verloop - that I&amp;rsquo;ve come to feel like going back on the chase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/articles/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 23:02:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/articles/test/</guid>
      <description>Insert Lead paragraph here.
A augue nunc lacus auctor efficitur tempor placerat, dictum volutpat mi vitae viverra porta non sem, himenaeos senectus vivamus potenti cubilia sollicitudin. Curae cursus inceptos tincidunt magna mi nibh ad enim etiam, molestie eu quis primis hendrerit taciti phasellus. Feugiat ultricies dictumst iaculis potenti odio laoreet urna at, ultrices curae leo accumsan proin sem lobortis.
Heading 2 Sollicitudin ornare odio blandit aenean enim lacus accumsan elementum vestibulum porta mauris lorem, ullamcorper class fermentum sem hendrerit ante augue penatibus scelerisque felis leo proin,ad nascetur venenatis sodales dignissim viverra suspendisse turpis convallis condimentum sapien.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Linkedin | Github | Twitter
Hiya! You found me. I&amp;rsquo;m Nirant.
I build Machine Learning/Data Science powered products. I make sometimes clever products which make human life easier.
Past NLP in Python: Quickstart Guide Wrote a Book for Programmers to Brew NLP Recipes (Jan 2019)

 Written with code examples and programmer-first mindset. Try it out yourself on Github Includes Text Embedding, Linguistics 101, Ensemble Modeling, Chatbots with small data, ML and Deep learning for text classification using tools like spaCy, PyTorch, &amp;amp; gensim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bezos &amp; Amazon Inc.</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/amazon/</guid>
      <description>Bezos &amp;amp; Amazon Inc. This short page is my personal collection of lessons, ideas, observation, &amp;amp; notes.
I don&amp;rsquo;t expect them to be useful for anyone except me, but hey - if you do, say Hi to me on Twitter
Introductory This is mostly obvious stuff. - Book - The Everything Store - Betting on Things that Never Change by Morgan Housel
Observations These are nebulous ideas or dots. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how they connect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fail Resume</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/failresume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/failresume/</guid>
      <description>A failure resume is, as its name suggests, a list of rejections and setbacks.
This concept originated in academia, but can be applied to improve one’s career, resilience, and approach to challenges in any walk of life.
I’ve organized my setbacks by year (starting with 2016), and what constitutes a “failure” here is based solely on my own judgement. It’s important to not only list the failures, but also learn from them, so I will add reflections to some of them (in progress).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Talk Tips</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/techtalktips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/techtalktips/</guid>
      <description>Collection of the Best Advice on Internet that I know about on giving a tech talk. Based on responses from my question on Twitter.
 You: Hey, I know something better!
Me: Please tell me about it! Raise a PR. Or reply to the tweet above!
 The Mindset  Presentations Skills Considered Harmful tl;dr: Do not block the message with your actions. Put in the work to get the message across.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>