<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drafts on Nirant Kasliwal</title>
    <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drafts on Nirant Kasliwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:09:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nirantk.com/drafts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Find Frontiers of Software Craft</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/how-to-find-frontiers-of-software-craft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/how-to-find-frontiers-of-software-craft/</guid>
      <description>Like most of my essays, this essay is written for myself from few years ago.
Software Engineering, and it&amp;rsquo;s cousins like Computer Science are unique. Unlike relatively mature domains of say, linear algebra - the field is still growing and not yet coherent. That makes it some what hard to study and master.
This also means we have a unique opportunity here. This makes it better to work in a field which is not yet c</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Org Designs</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/data-org-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/data-org-design/</guid>
      <description>Data Science Org Design While there is plenty of good advice on making ML work and making a career as a Data Scientist - I think very little discussion happens on the organization design for Data Science itself.
 Organization Design is determined by these 3 broad categories:
  Software Engineer vs Research: To what extent is the Machine Learning team responsible for building or integrating with software? How important are Software Engineering skills on the team?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inconsequential Success</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/inconsequential-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/inconsequential-success/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re all Gamers Now</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/stop-larping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/stop-larping/</guid>
      <description>When I show up to Dr. Bob’s office, I don’t expect to deal with Bob; I expect to deal with The Doctor. The doctor is not going to behave as Bob, Alice, or Caroline might act, even if that’s who the doctor is. The doctor is going to behave as The Doctor! This is essentially a human user interface. I’m not Samo. I am The Patient. And Alice is The Doctor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: Building a Data Science Team at a Startup</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/case-study-building-a-data-science-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/case-study-building-a-data-science-team/</guid>
      <description>Hello!
If we are meeting for the first time, a short version of my story so far: After doing research engineering for almost 4 years across startups and a BigCo, I joined as an early machine learning engineer at Verloop.io - a B2B startup that makes customer support automation SaaS. We&amp;rsquo;re directly responsible for most Natural Language Processing needs within the business.
While there is plenty of good advice on making ML work and making a career as a Data Scientist, I wanted to write my experience as a manager/early engineer who built out a ML team at a startup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Career Notes</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/careernotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/careernotes/</guid>
      <description>Who is this for? This is written for me, 5 years ago - when I was starting my career in Data Science. You can treat these as Notes/Advice/Rant/Opinion.
That said, I expect this to be helpful to:
  Early to Mid Career Folks in Engineering roles considering moving to ML/Data Science
  Primarily written for those in India
 Rant: If you&amp;rsquo;re not in India and any of this applies to you, please consider hiring a career coach - you&amp;rsquo;ve too much low hanging fruit in planning your career    Rant: Note that the most obnoxious, random comments will be marked by Rant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roles, Theatre and Girard</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/theatre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/theatre/</guid>
      <description>Role Models and Distance Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s Outgroup
https://alexdanco.com/2019/04/28/secrets-about-people-a-short-and-dangerous-introduction-to-rene-girard/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hinglish</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/hinglish/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/hinglish/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice for Breaking into NLP outside Academia</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/breaking-into-nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/breaking-into-nlp/</guid>
      <description>Bulk of this is borrowed from notes made my teammate and friend at Verloop.io&amp;rsquo;s NLP/ML team of our conversations. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the liberty to remove our internal slang, abuses and some boring stuff.
Asker: I want to build a community around me on NLP. How can I get discovered by others?
NK: Broadly speaking, the aim in forming connections can be split into Long Term and Short term. A short term aim would be where you can receive something immediate out of the connections or a particular connection itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Character is Net Worth</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/character-is-net-worth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/character-is-net-worth/</guid>
      <description>Being Nice is a Safety Net with Holes Measured Skills are an Operation Expense Unmeasured but Marketed Skills is an Asset Class #TODO finish this thought If I gave you 100,000 Rs today - what would you do with that? If you are
What I found useful when thinking about these ideas: [1] Status as a Service: https://www.eugenewei.com/blog/2019/2/19/status-as-a-service [2] Keep your identity small: http://www.paulgraham.com/identity.html
Reputation is Insurance In India, Amazon is known for a superior customer service than it&amp;rsquo;s home grown rival: Flipkart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening Quotes</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/openingquotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/openingquotes/</guid>
      <description>“ये जो लोग-बाग हैं जंगल की आग हैं क्यूँ आग में जलूँ&amp;hellip; ये नाकाम प्यार में खुश हैं ये हार में इन जैसा क्यूँ बनूँ&amp;hellip;”
We have all worked so hard to achieve mediocrity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prosumer</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/prosumer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/prosumer/</guid>
      <description>Keys: :raising_hand: What I&amp;rsquo;ve tried :100: Awesome, recommend :ear: Hearing good things about this :eyes: Keeping an eye on this
The Celebs Superhuman Airtable Notion Emerging Coda (h/t @CaseyNewton)
TickTick (to-do&amp;rsquo;s) (h/t @CaseyNewton)
Woven (calendar) (h/t @CaseyNewton)
The Just Born Tandem.chat Good problem, incomplete solutions: Breaker (podcasts but social) (h/t @CaseyNewton)
Soon (Goodreads but for all other media) (h/t @CaseyNewton)
Stoop (RSS reader for newsletters) (h/t @CaseyNewton)
The Quirky Google Sheets Solutions SteinHQ https://steinhq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/bigco-vs-startups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/bigco-vs-startups/</guid>
      <description>https://danluu.com/startup-tradeoffs/#fnref:S
Beyond First 90 Days - 2 Less Obvious Ideas
I am assuming that you already know the hygiene factors: Make few promises. Keep most of them and exceed few of them atleast. Get to like the top 5% in the skill of effort estimation for your own work at the very least. And so on.
Contribute to Developer Ecosystem Improving any part of the developer ecosystem is useful and visible at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/invisible-algo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/invisible-algo/</guid>
      <description>Logistic Regression was perhaps the algorithm with most far reaching and invisible algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/metamorphosis-moment-for-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/metamorphosis-moment-for-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Editor&amp;rsquo;s Note 0: I&amp;rsquo;ve no editor. Editor&amp;rsquo;s Note 1: I use the terms machine learning, data science and AI interchangeably, just to annoy people who take terms too seriosuly. E.g. me
Palantir is proving the limits of data science insights: https://simplystatistics.org/2020/08/26/palantir-shows-its-cards/
Greylock&amp;rsquo;s Systems of Intelligence
TikTok is violating the limits of data science baked into products
Data Products are hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/read-cs-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/read-cs-papers/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/sprezzatura/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/sprezzatura/</guid>
      <description>One of the most interesting shifts and paradigms of last 20-30 years in Indian elite circles was the acceptance for what I call high visibility hard work. For instance, some of the most popular enterpreneurs of today openly talk about hard it is.
This has few interesting outcomes:
 It helps people understand that there is a deep and personal cost to doing hard things e.g. enterpreneurship It also summarily led to the rejection of &amp;ldquo;Passion hypothesis&amp;rdquo; i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bezos &amp; Amazon Inc.</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/drafts/amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/drafts/amazon/</guid>
      <description>This short page is my personal collection of lessons, ideas, observation, &amp;amp; notes. They mostly concern Bezos, with some love for Ambani as well.
I don&amp;rsquo;t expect them to be useful for anyone except me, but hey - if you do, say Hi to me on Twitter
Mega-Tech of the Future  ReCode Podcast - How Jim Collins Helped Amazon Rescue Itself Peter Thiel tells Eric Schimdt in 2012 that Amazon is the only mega-tech that knows how to invest in the future What is Amazon?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
