<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nirant Kasliwal on</title><link>https://nirantk.com/contributors/nirant-kasliwal/</link><description>Recent content in Nirant Kasliwal on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 23:29:18 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nirantk.com/contributors/nirant-kasliwal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Retrieval Augmented Generation Best Practices</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/rag-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/rag-best-practices/</guid><description>Retrieval and Ranking Matter! #
Chunking #
Including section title in your chunks improves that, so does keywords from the documents Different token-efficient separators in your chunks e.g. ### is a single token in GPT Examples #
Few examples are better than no examples Examples at the start and end have the highest weight, the middle ones are kinda forgotten by the LLM Re Rankers #
Latency permitting — use a ReRanker — Cohere, Sentence Transformers and BGE have decent ones out of the box</description></item><item><title>Tax Tips for Consultants with Foreign Income</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/foreign-income/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/foreign-income/</guid><description>Managing taxation and financial compliance as a consultant in India involves several considerations: GST to the benefits of Section 44ADA and the complexities of foreign entity considerations, consultants must juggle multiple aspects to ensure compliance and tax optimization. I&amp;rsquo;m sharing what I know in the hopes it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to others.
1. Compliance: GST, LUT and FIRC #
Threshold: Acquiring a GST number becomes almost mandatory once your income surpasses some X=20 lakhs INR in a given financial year.</description></item><item><title>Meetup Parameters</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/meetup-params/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/meetup-params/</guid><description>This is based on organising GenerativeAI Meetups in Bengaluru, India. This is a living document and will be updated as we learn more.
Venue #
Date &amp;amp; Time &amp;amp; Duration: Choose suitable timing and duration. Pick something that works for your community. Consider weekday and weekend meetups both. Example: 4:00-5.00pm start on a Saturday works great in BLR! Chennai did a GenAI meetup on Saturday morning &amp;ndash; since that city wakes up early, it worked well for them.</description></item><item><title>AI4Humans: Software x LLMs</title><link>https://nirantk.com/talks/ai4bharat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/talks/ai4bharat/</guid><description>AI4Bharat, IIT Madras, July 2023
Namaste! 🙏 I&amp;rsquo;m Nirant and here&amp;rsquo;s a brief of what we discussed in our session.
Why You Should Care? #
I have a track record in the field of NLP and machine learning, including a paper at ACL 2020 on Hinglish, the first Hindi-LM, and an NLP book with over 5000 copies sold. I&amp;rsquo;ve contributed to IndicGlue by AI4Bharat, built and deployed systems used by Nykaa, and consulted for healthcare enterprises and YC companies.</description></item><item><title>Qdrant vs pgvector - Results from the 1M OpenAI Benchmark</title><link>https://nirantk.com/writing/pgvector-vs-qdrant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/pgvector-vs-qdrant/</guid><description>You may have considered using PostgreSQL&amp;rsquo;s pgvector extension for vector similarity search. There are good reasons why this option is strictly inferior to dedicated vector search engines, such as Qdrant.
We ran both benchmarks using the ann-benchmarks solely dedicated to processing vector data. The difference in performance is quite staggering.
Query Speed #
Final results show that pgvector lags behind Qdrant by a factor of 15 when it comes to throughput.</description></item><item><title>Exploring AI Applications, Ethics, and OpenAI's Closed Source Approach</title><link>https://nirantk.com/docs/resources/summaries/7th-may-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/docs/resources/summaries/7th-may-2023/</guid><description>OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s decision to not do closed source #
OpenAI Chief Scientist Ilya S. explains that OpenAI is not doing closed source because of safety reasons, but because of competitive reasons. He believes models can be improved to the point in the future where it becomes a safety concern. Competitive reasons #
The competitive reasons mentioned by Ilya S. refer to Microsoft, which is a major investor in OpenAI. Microsoft has been known to use closed source models in the past, which gives them a competitive advantage.</description></item><item><title>Generative AI Group Chat: Resources, Hackathons, and Model Discussions</title><link>https://nirantk.com/docs/resources/summaries/6th-may-2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/docs/resources/summaries/6th-may-2023/</guid><description>Introduction #
Group chat transcript on Generative AI Chaotic discussion on various topics Learning Resources #
Link to a post on what transformers are Cohere has two of the best ML content creators List of top AI-themed newsletters shared 42papers.com recommended Ben&amp;rsquo;s Bites newsletter recommended Hackathon #
Invitation to join a team in Warpspeed GenAI hackathon Deterministic Output #
Discussion on making GPT2 or BLOOM model outputs consistent Two ways to make it deterministic: setting temp=0 or setting seeds Pro tip to pursue this line of reasoning and gain first-hand experience Visual Aesthetic Scoring #
Discussion on AVA dataset and image dataset curation methods Link to a space on huggingface for aesthetic predictor Use of clip interrogator to score generated captions Hallucination and determinism are not related Visual aesthetic scoring is largely a final layer problem Discussion on the limitations of the model Dataset Creation #
Request for good library references to create datasets for LLMs Discussion on creating a dataset based on few hand-written examples Suggestion to check the terms of service for commercial use Discussion on using a visual QA model to identify errors in a picture Workflow suggestion to detect errors in the image and fix them using models finetuned on those datasets Suggestion to use Andrew Ng&amp;rsquo;s landing.</description></item><item><title>OpenAI, Google Models, and Hugging Face Developments</title><link>https://nirantk.com/docs/resources/summaries/5th-may-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/docs/resources/summaries/5th-may-2023/</guid><description>OpenAI and Google models:
Google models have no moat OpenAI may have a moat due to early mover advantage and alignment with Microsoft/Azure OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s moat may come from government and finance domains OpenAI may be able to maintain its lead for 2 to 5 years or more Open source models are far behind OpenAI currently, but may catch up eventually Network effects may not be a moat in this case Microsoft+OpenAI can make inference costs low and onboard other businesses on plugins Hugging Face:</description></item><item><title>Generative AI in Digital Painting and Large Scale Dataset Creation</title><link>https://nirantk.com/docs/resources/summaries/4th-may-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/docs/resources/summaries/4th-may-2023/</guid><description>Introduction and greetings
Members introduce themselves and exchange pleasantries Generative AI for digital painting
Discussion on the potential for creating artist-focused digital painting tools using Generative AI Current methods involve hacking with automatic tools and using Photoshop to achieve desired results Large scale dataset creation for LLM model training
Member asks if anyone has experience creating large scale datasets Links #
The description and link can be mismatched because of extraction errors.</description></item><item><title>Generative AI Group Chat Highlights</title><link>https://nirantk.com/docs/resources/summaries/3rd-may-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://nirantk.com/docs/resources/summaries/3rd-may-2023/</guid><description>Topics Discussed in Chaotic Generative AI Group Chat Transcript #
AI Models and Tools #
GPT4 creates a vector DB Replit open source LLM just dropped Finetune on instruction dataset curated from geeksforgeeks Prompt Injection in less than 10 minutes (video, slides, transcripts) JSONFormer: guaranteed JSON output with Huggingface LLMs DeepFloyd or Multi-ControlNet? Is there a model (other than gpt4) that can extract info from an image in JSON format? Autogpt app Table-transformer might help if result cards are in tabular form AI Applications #
Abstract artwork made using stable diffusion Extracting values without OCR Parsing information from result cards Langflow AI Industry and Innovation #
India&amp;rsquo;s position in the generative AI race Chris Lattner&amp;rsquo;s new ML-focused language Ecosystem graphs for AI startups Networking and Collaboration #
Connecting with others in the group for contribution and collaboration Looking for journalists or media folks in the group Miscellaneous #
Group invite link request AI and art techniques OpenAI service on Azure Multi-modal GPT4 access Sanford C.</description></item></channel></rss>