<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>career on Nirant Kasliwal</title>
    <link>https://nirantk.com/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in career on Nirant Kasliwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:09:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nirantk.com/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing Out at Work</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/standout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/standout/</guid>
      <description>In my short career, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some amazing young people stand out at work.
Here is what they did, organized by 5 themes:
 Unlock Knowledge
 Automate Boring Stuff
 Write Widely
 Solve Open Problems
 Outside-Visible Work
  Unlock Knowledge Expertise and know-how stay trapped in emails, docs and codebases. Unlock this for everyone else.
Get your Star Salesman on an internal podcast to spill their secrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking of Your Career as a Startup</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/ruleof40/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/ruleof40/</guid>
      <description>Broadly speaking, it’s useful to think of your career as a startup.
Your profit+growth percentage should be a minimum 40%
So say, you join a big company like Microsoft and your skills grow at 20% every year, while your pay only grows 10% - that&amp;rsquo;s bad.
You need to grow your skills and outcomes faster.
The other extreme is also fine: You join a small startup which can make great use of entrepreneurial DNA plus specific skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to prepare for a Data Science job from college?</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/datasciencejob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/datasciencejob/</guid>
      <description>A Getting Started Guide
Let us get our facts straight, shall we?
I am writing from my non-existent but probably relevant experience. I worked in a Machine Learning role at Samsung Research, Bengaluru. It is only 1 of the 4 research enterprises which hire Machine Learning researchers from Indian colleges — the other being Microsoft, Xerox, and IBM Watson.
I am now in a even more Computer Vision focused role for a small enterprise tech company.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>