<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>personal on Nirant Kasliwal</title>
    <link>https://nirantk.com/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in personal on Nirant Kasliwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nirantk.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fail Resume</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/failresume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/failresume/</guid>
      <description>A failure resume is, as its name suggests, a list of rejections and setbacks.
This concept originated in academia, but can be applied to improve one’s career, resilience, and approach to challenges in any walk of life.
I’ve organized my setbacks by year (starting with 2016), and what constitutes a “failure” here is based solely on my own judgement. It’s important to not only list the failures, but also learn from them, so I will add reflections to some of them (in progress).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/now/</guid>
      <description>What I’m doing now Work: I look at Machine Learning and Natural Language stuff for Verloop. We help make customer support more humane.
Career: Rather scattered and still exploratory
Torschlusspaniki About the word Torschlusspaniki
My previous workplaces made a serious dent in the size of my dreams.
Psychological safety is a weird concept. I wish more leaders understood this intuitively.
Last Updated in October 2019 from Bengaluru, India
The concept of now page is from Derek Sivers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hiya! I&amp;rsquo;m Nirant! It means the calm of the forest in Gujarati, Sanskrit and Prakrit. The last two are languages, all but lost to time.
3 things I want you to know about me: 1. Make $$ doing NLP. Even wrote a book about NLP. I talk a lot about it too. 2. I write blogs about career, technology and business: Newsletter 3. I&amp;rsquo;m always happy to help those who ask crisp and descriptive questions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>