<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>career on Nirant Kasliwal</title>
    <link>https://nirantk.com/tags/career.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in career on Nirant Kasliwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:09:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nirantk.com/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First 90 Days - Software Engineer Version</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/first-90-days-engineer-version.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/first-90-days-engineer-version.html</guid>
      <description>Aditya Ankur, asked me:
I know that there is a book for the first 90 days as an executive. Is there something similar for programmers?
I don&amp;rsquo;t quite know of a book/essay which covers this yet sticks to the question. So I am writing one for him.
The First 90 Days for a New Engineer I expect each step to take roughly between 10 and 30 days, depending on the pace of your project + size of the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verloop NLP Interview Prep Guide</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/verloop-ml-prep-guide.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/verloop-ml-prep-guide.html</guid>
      <description>Preparation Guide I&amp;rsquo;ve been an early Machine Learning Engineer at Verloop.io for almost 1.5 years, primarily working on NLP problems and now more in an Engineering Manager-ish role.
This is the guide which I sometimes send to our candidates after they submit the Programming Challenge. If a candidate has relevant open source code sample, specially to other repositories we may choose to waive off the Programming Challenge completely.
I originally wrote this to give a chance to folks coming from non-NLP background to get a sense of the problem space a little better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talent Cooling</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/talentcooling.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/talentcooling.html</guid>
      <description>Talent Cooling Kills Startup Growth Evaporative Cooling [1] occurs when the most high value contributors to a community realize that the community is no longer serving their needs any more and so therefore, leave.
Then something remarkably interesting happens:
 When that happens, it drops the general quality of the community down such that the next most high value contributors now find the community underwhelming. Each layer of disappearances slowly reduces the average quality of the group until such a point that you reach the people who are so unskilled-and-unaware of it that they’re unable to tell that they’re part of a mediocre group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing Out at Work</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/standout.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/standout.html</guid>
      <description>In my short career, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some amazing young people stand out at work.
Here is what they did, organized by 5 themes:
  Unlock Knowledge
  Automate Boring Stuff
  Write Widely
  Solve Open Problems
  Outside-Visible Work
  Unlock Knowledge Expertise and know-how stay trapped in emails, docs and codebases. Unlock this for everyone else.
Get your Star Salesman on an internal podcast to spill their secrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Act Like You&#39;re 35</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/actlike35.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/actlike35.html</guid>
      <description>Don’t just network with people your own age Beware the whiz kid syndrome. Smart, young people have a habit of forming communities of other smart young people and feeding off each other’s energy. Argghhhh. Are you not just making mistakes made by older people again? Make original mistakes
Youth enclaves can actually be restrictive. In fact their networking should be about meeting useful mentors and career champions who can open doors and fast track careers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking of Your Career as a Startup</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/ruleof40.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/ruleof40.html</guid>
      <description>Broadly speaking, it’s useful to think of your career as a startup.
Your profit+growth percentage should be a minimum 40%
So say, you join a big company like Microsoft and your skills grow at 20% every year, while your pay only grows 10% - that&amp;rsquo;s bad.
You need to grow your skills and outcomes faster.
The other extreme is also fine: You join a small startup which can make great use of entrepreneurial DNA plus specific skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picking a Startup Team You Want to Work With</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/picking-startup-to-work-with.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/picking-startup-to-work-with.html</guid>
      <description>Why we need to do a reference check on startup teams we work with? Great Startups always ask someone who is joining for a reference check. They speak to your previous managers and colleagues. There is no reason why candidates should not do the same. Many startup employees have more opportunity costs than the founders themselves.
I&amp;rsquo;m surprised by the lack of due diligence which candidates do when interviewing with us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to prepare for a Data Science job from college?</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/datasciencejob.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 23:29:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/datasciencejob.html</guid>
      <description>A Getting Started Guide
Let us get our facts straight, shall we?
I am writing from my non-existent but probably relevant experience. I worked in a Machine Learning role at Samsung Research, Bengaluru. It is only 1 of the 4 research enterprises which hire Machine Learning researchers from Indian colleges — the other being Microsoft, Xerox, and IBM Watson.
I am now in a even more Computer Vision focused role for a small enterprise tech company.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
