<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notes for self on Nirant Kasliwal</title>
    <link>https://nirantk.com/tags/notes-for-self/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notes for self on Nirant Kasliwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:09 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nirantk.com/tags/notes-for-self/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Bask in Reflected Glory</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/reflectedglory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/reflectedglory/</guid>
      <description>ये जो लोग-बाग हैं, जंगल की आग हैं Ye jo log baag hain, Jungle ki aag hain The people, are jungle fire क्यूँ आग में जलूँ... Kyun aag mein jalun Why should I burn in the fire? ये नाकाम प्यार में, खुश हैं ये हार में Ye nakaam pyaar mein, Khush hai yeh haar mein Defeated in love, they&#39;re happy in defeat इन जैसा क्यूँ बनूँ... Inn jaisa kyun banun Why should I be like them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Good Fight</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/goodfight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/goodfight/</guid>
      <description>In the first few pages of the book Born Standing Up, Steve says something poignant:
 One can have, it turns out, an affection for the war years.
 He was someone chasing something external: fame, glory, money or a version of these. Yet, in his dusk years — once he had achieved some of those, he valued his struggle more than his fame and glory.
For Steve, it was not about achieving these, it was, as I have come to call it: a good fight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does anything we do matter?</title>
      <link>https://nirantk.com/writing/do/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nirantk.com/writing/do/</guid>
      <description>Part I I once travelled in a crowded dusty general compartment of our lovely Indian Railways from Mumbai to Hyderabad. I left from Mumbai on an evening train. Across me, sat a man with a silver beard in a Gandhi topi, white kurta and black jeans. He had a black laptop bag filled with what sounded like chocolate wrappers. When his phone rang, I heard him take a call in prosaic English.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>